Hello friends, I am Rakesh Sandesh, a
very warm welcome to all of you on my channel.
Term insurance and home loan protection
plan, in layman's language, or
common man, both have the same purpose.
If we talk about term insurance, then
in the customer's option, his family members get the
money, whatever you get done, if I
talk about home loan protection plan, then
again in the customer's option, if there is a
protest for home loan, that
money is given to the family members. Now
friends, both are considered to have the same purpose and there is a
comparison in the premium. If we
talk about term insurance or railway, there is a
difference of earth and sky in the premium of both and the purpose of both is
also considered to be the same, but the purpose of both is actually
different. Now friends,
how are these purposes different? Both are actually
considered to be the same. I am going to clear this confusion from you.
Friends, watch the video carefully from beginning to end in this video.
If you like the video, then like it.
Friends, for such updated information related to finance, subscribe to my channel
and press the bell icon so that
You get confirmation of every upcoming video
regularly, friends, let's start
today's too, friends, like we discussed in the beginning,
eat these two,
in reality, a common man considers the purpose of both to be the same,
but if I tell you its real
purpose, then it is that
any insurance that
you take should have the purpose of covering these securities,
not that you weigh it and
go into whose premium is being earned, many times it happens that
in choosing a low premium,
you actually ignore the security that your family needs,
but friends, this does not mean that
and I am not saying that
you should take a product insurance with a high premium,
at the beginning of this video, first of all,
friends, I want to tell you
that our motive behind making this video is
whether you were able to identify which insurance is suitable for you and your family in actual,
now friends, as I told you, its main purpose should be to
cover the insecurities of family members in the feature,
not low
premium  Please enable how to
cover other things within this. This should be done. Now
I would like to tell you the competition between both term insurance and HLP. So I would like to
start with the
definition of both. Term insurance is generally
considered a type of life insurance or people like to
call it that which you have taken
respectfully. No matter for how long,
every tempered glass and tears for fears,
it does its work as long as you pay the premium within a year. If
it is not covered within a year, then no
problem, next year
you revise that premium again
and in this way, God forbid, you ever
need it. It comes in handy after a customer is kidnapped. If I
talk about activity, as
long as you have taken a home loan, it is a
loan of 15 years. Whatever is the
tenure of the home loan, it covers only your loan amount within it.
Friends,
if we compare the premium of both, then
comparatively the premium of term insurance
is less and for example, if you have taken
insurance of even 1 crore, its premium will be
20%.  If the age of the individual is in the range of 25 to 30 years, then
its premium generally
falls in the range of 18 to 20000. In the same way,
if you take a home loan protection plan, then
if the home loan is of 40 or 50 lakhs, then
its premium is quite high. Now,
in the premium also, there are two types of plans. I am
talking about home loan protection plan,
one is level up and the other is
reducing plan. This level plan has
its principal cover. Suppose you have taken a loan of this amount,
you have a home loan protection
plan. Now, five or six years pass under it,
then whatever amount of 3 lakhs or
4 lakhs you have reduced, that is your
principal, that will be covered under your level up plan,
whose premium is a little higher.
Suppose, out of your 30 lakhs, 10
lakhs is the principal, still if you have taken the level up
premium and have taken the liver cover, then
your family members get the total fixed
amount only, even if you
cannot increase it. Therefore, in the same way, if there is reducing plan of 25 lakhs, then the amount of
outstanding  The
amount is Option A. Prince William and
your family members get it. Generally, it is
not more accurate than what the family members get. The
insurance company deposits the outstanding amount in the bank
and then if the documents have changed etc.,
only the property papers of this house are given to your family members, then
it gets covered
under both the second and the third party coverage. Friends,
as I told you about the
coverage, you
can also modify it under term insurance. Suppose
you have taken Panchayat coverage till now and
you have adjusted your premium accordingly,
but going forward, you feel that
I want to increase its coverage for another 10 years, then there is a
premium for this, in
which it is done and
you can increase your coverage, but in the home loan production
plant, your coverage will be considered only for the tenure of your loan. The first
point is modification. Friends, if you
want to modify the term insurance, then
it can be modified.
Respectively, whichever inspector you have
taken, you can increase the tender for it.  If I
talk about the notification in both the plans and Airtel, then this
Stratford remains the same.
Whatever premium you have taken,
your loan mode is covered till the completion.
It remains the same and remains constant. The
point is tax benefit friends,
in the premium of both, under Section 80C of Income Tax Act 1961,
you
get a benefit of up to Rs. 1,50,000.
If you talk about it like this, then apart from this,
under Section 2004 also you get a
benefit of up to two lakhs in additional interest.
Then the point is advance boss. Till now there
was no provision of any kind of dont in Palm Insurance, which means whatever
insurance you have taken, it remains on this platform;
no other riders are added in it. Till now there was a rider
in SSP also,
but now a new rider has been added, for example, if you lose
your job, now
for security, the rider is covered within three to six months. In case of some other
problem like critical
illness, you get the benefit of 3 to 6 months in this also
and the insurance is
covered.  It is said that till now no disease was covered under term insurance,
but whether it is cancer or office, all these
diseases are covered now. Now friends,
I have told you the comparison of both
with an example, still some people prefer term insurance
because its
premium is less and the premium of HIV
is higher and it is possible that if the
amount in term insurance was more, there would have been a
problem of 1 crore in it, but
friends, now I am going to tell you one more thing
with which your
mindset may change, this is the concept of
human life value. Airtel Mica,
if I want to explain to you the concept of human life value, there is
a very simple
example, there is a huge difference between my income and Bill Gates'
income, if
I wanted to take my insurance coverage as per Bill Gates, then the
insurance company
refused me. This is a general account based on
your annual income. If you are looking for 18 to 35 lakhs, then
you get coverage up to 25 lakhs of your annual income, if you fall in a range of 3650 then
You get coverage up to 120 times of your annual income and such
words of tears for fears come to your mind, then
we get coverage for 10225 types of annual income, now
friends, if I take care of this, then it is
possible that for the coverage of Vanshya, the
annual income capacity of a customer may be less
or it has already been activated, now for that also you have to provide
proof of income, 3 years'
income tax return, your bank statement,
these should match, actually
for the coverage of Vanshya, suppose you have done the
coverage of your family, even after this
your family needs protection,
I will explain this to you further, suppose
after taking a loan of Rs. 1000, you have bought a house of 15x the amount, you have taken a
home loan,
relax that God forbid some problem occurs for the home loan, then
you will have to pay the
premium only to cover the home loan,
from Vanshya almost
it has gone into your home loan, the rest of the family
members only  Only 50% amount is available,
so friends, there can be a disadvantage here
that you have not taken additional coverage, if
your point is activated with your coverage, then you
get extra protection and for
example, you have taken a home loan protection plan for a
loan of 15x, then tomorrow if it
goes to its exclusive home loan college
and your family member can get the entire one shared
amount, so friends, here
we are considering the premium only as premium,
your actual purpose
and the motive of covering the insecurities of the family matters
more,
now here for instant coverage, a
deposit has to be filled, so I
leave it to you to decide whether you should actually
take it or not, if
in the end result, someone personally agrees, then
it can be discussed, so
friends, I hope you liked this video of mine,
if you like this video, then
like it, friends, get such
updated information related to finance, friends, subscribe to my channel
and press the bell icon so that
every person coming here can get this information.  Keep meeting
regularly See you next 9
News Room
[Music]
Loot lo kar
do